# Richard Chiriboga

Flushing, NY 11355 (347) 326-4434 RichardChiriboga@gmail.com https://Linkedin.com/in/richardchiriboga http://richardchiriboga.com

Driven and collaborative Technical Manager with extensive experience in web development and management, across non-profit, boutique agency and global company environments. Expertise in leading website restructuring and development projects, corporate intranet builds, and content management plans through their complete life cycle – from ideation to launch. Known for being a trusted partner across multiple vendors, functions and disciplines, and having the ability to communicate complex information to both technical and non-technical users. Offers Hispanic marketing and social media expertise: Created award-winning website CorrienteLatina.com. Fluent in English, with intermediate Spanish fluency.

#### **Skills**

- Technical Management
- Web Development Management
- Waterfall / Agile Methodologies
- Digital Media / Marketing
- Front-End Web Development
- GitHub
- PHP / MySQL
- WordPress

- HTML / CSS / Javascript
- jQuery / Angular JS
- Certified ScrumMaster
- Luminate CMS / Online

# **Experience**

11/2016 - 12/2017

# Senior Manager, Web Development / Avon Breast Cancer Crusade, New York, NY

Managed web development team along with all project life cycles while bridging the gap between cross-functional internal and external stakeholders to deliver a seamless digital solution using waterfall and agile methodology.

- Managed brand IT relationships and strategy with internal and remote third-party vendors across various projects. This included project SOW's, resources, budgets and conflict resolution.
- Implemented and standardized web design/development workflow to ensure updates and new functionality were pushed seamlessly.
- Lead web development tasks, including user interface, systems architecture, platform logic, API development, maintenance for all our web properties.
- Standardized the email signature throughout the entire company by creating an online form that allowed staff to create a standardized email signature and easily add it to our Gmail environment.
- Led I.T. crisis management which included SSL and payment gateway issues.
- Developed an online check-in system used throughout the 2015-2017 event seasons. The "Check-In Friday" system allowed volunteers and staff to manage and report on participants and crew during physical event weekends.

06/2011 - 11/2016

## Manager, Web Technologies / Avon Products Inc., New York, NY

Managed all web properties owned by the Corporate Communications department such as the "InsideAvon" global intranet and corporate website - AvonCompany.com.

- Addressed corporate Intranet (InsideAvon) issues by spearheading and leading the front-end development effort to
  create a custom CMS built on .NET MVC, Twitter Bootstrap, jQuery and knockout.js. Equipped with movable dynamic
  widgets and a simple image manipulator, it enabled content owners to update their respective websites effortlessly.
  InsideAvon housed 25 market and functional intranets.
- Improved associates digital experience by utilizing the latest trends to create a holistic socially interactive digital
  workplace. This included being part of the steering committee that rolled out Microsoft Office 365 to over 30,000
  associates to replace Lotus Notes.
- Helped plan all aspects of project development including scope, objectives, deliverables, tasks, budgets, resources, schedules, coordinating cross-functional teams, and managing dependencies.
- Successfully managed Web Portals using various Content Management Systems for global functions like Human Resources, Finance, Legal and Global Travel Security.
- Liaison between IT teams, design team and business product owners to help gather requirements and create spec documents for critical projects.

06/2007 - 07/2010

## Senior Web Developer / THAT Agency, West Palm Beach, FL

Worked directly with the president and project manager on all aspects from concept to creation for client websites.

- Part of leadership team that helped steer overall company on what technologies should be used for our spectrum of clients.
- Distinguished ourselves from other web boutiques by creating a custom content management system built in house and custom to each of our clients.
- Wrote technical blogs that allowed some of my web development work to be featured on quite a few "Top 10" lists for HTML/CSS/jQuery.

#### **Education**

05/2015

Certified ScrumMaster / Scrum Alliance, New York, NY

1993-1996

Informational Systems / Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY

#### **Activities**

I have owned and managed my own website since 2005, which markets entertainment news, advanced movie screenings and events. We won a Tecla Award for "Best Latino News and Culture" website by Hispanicize / Telemundo. I am an avid music listener and movie buff. I also volunteer web development time to a few nonprofits including "Travel with Purpose", "Stop Bullying Tour" and "Hair We Care". I had the privilege of being honored by Jack Daniels as 2017 Jack

Daniel's Neighborhood Flavors Honoree for the "Movers & S Queens, NY.	hakers" category for helping the Hispanic Community in